University of Waterloo Co-operative Work Terms

Ryan Shim 20783691 1B Architectural Engineering, Honours, Co-operative Program

No Co-op Work Term History available

Planned Future Work Term(s)

Sep - Dec 2019

May - Aug 2020

Jan - Apr 2021

Sep - Dec 2021

Sep - Dec 2022

Ryan Shim

416-822-0455| rshim@uwaterloo.ca| University of Waterloo| Architectural Engineering

May 21, 2019

Ryan Shim 98 Havagal Crescent. Markham, ON L3P 7G2

Dear Hiring Manager,

It is with great enthusiasm that I am applying to your company for a 4-month work term. I have experience using many languages (Python, MySQL, HTML5, and CSS3) and technologies (Bootstrap4, ReactJs, NodeJs) that will help me for the job. I believe that I have the skillset and motivation to succeed and improve while working for you.

My side projects include a weather app in ReactJs that gets weather API data to display the forecast at cities all over the world. It required knowledge about how to pass state and props, creating a user interface, and how to include search functionality. I have also built a portfolio website that uses Javascript animations, HTML5, CSS3, and the Bootstrap 4 framework. Features include page navigation and responsiveness at different screen sizes. In Python, I have made a solitaire game that uses the pygame library. It was a technically demanding project requiring in depth object oriented programming and creative array manipulation. Overall, I feel that my projects reflect my qualifications for this job.

Thank you for reading through my application and I hope to hear from you from your earliest convenience.

Kind Regards,

Ryan Shim

Ryan Shim

416-822-0455| rshim@uwaterloo.com | University of Waterloo | Architectural Engineering

LANGUAGES: Python, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

TECHNOLOGIES: Bootstrap4, ReactJs, NodeJs

PROJECTS/SKILLS

WEATHER APP

- Used ReactIs to build a weather app using weather API for data
- · Implemented search functionality to find weather in cities all over the world
- Used CSS3 and Bootstrap 4 to improve user interface

SOLITAIRE GAME

- Used Pygame library in Python to build a fully functional solitaire card game
- · Implemented object oriented programming for cards, decks, and piles

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE

- Built a portfolio website(<u>rvanshim.ca</u>) using HTML5, CSS3, and, the Bootstrap 4 framework
- Website implements grid system, Javascript animations, visually appealing layouts, and external fonts and icons

MICROSOFT OFFICE

- Strong excel skills shown by making spread sheets for work schedules as a camp counsellor
- Demonstrated ability to make engaging PowerPoint presentations in courses at school

All programming projects can be found on my Github: github.com/RyanShim2000

EXPERIENCES

EVENT COORDINATOR | UNIONVILLE YOUTH COUNCIL | OCTOBER 2017 - MAY 2018

- Organized, led, and promoted face painting and balloon animal events for two hundred children
- Managed four hundred dollars towards props: painting kits and balloons for participating children
- · Delegated different roles to team members of the council based on their strengths and abilities

CAMP COUNSELLOR | JUST FOR KIDS CAMP | SUMMER 2015 - 2017

- Demonstrated leadership abilities by promoting safety to campers when facilitating activities
- Built a large-scale snack menu that could feed over one hundred fifty campers

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

ARCHITECTURAL ENGINEERING CLASS REPRESENTATIVE AT WATERLOO UNIVERSITY | SEPTEMBER 2018 – PRESENT

Managed \$100,000 school funds with other engineering programs for student aid

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ARCHITECTURAL ENGINEERING, BASC | UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO | ANTICIPATED 2023

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO UNOFFICIAL GRADE REPORT

Ryan Shim 20783691

1B Architectural Engineering, Honours, Co-operative Program

Spring	2019
--------	------

AE	105	Mechanics 2		
AE	121	Computational Methods		
AE	125	Architectural Graphics Studio		
GENE	123	Elec Circuits & Instrument		
MATH	118	Calculus 2 for Engineering		
GENE	119	Problems Seminar		
Term A	verage: N/A	Decision:		

Winter 2019

MATH

PD	20		Eng'g Workplce Skills I:	CR		
	Term Average:	N/A	Decision:			
Fall 2018						
ΑE	100		Concepts Studio	76		
ΑE	101		History of Built Environment	73		
ΑE	104		Mechanics 1	92		
ΑE	115		Linear Algebra	84		
CH	IE 102		Chemistry for Engineers	71		

116 Calculus 1 for Engineering Term Average: 79 Decision: Good standing

87

Ryan Shim

416-822-0455| rshim@uwaterloo.com | University of Waterloo | Architectural Engineering

LANGUAGES: Python, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

TECHNOLOGIES: Bootstrap4, ReactJs, NodeJs

PROJECTS/SKILLS

WEATHER APP

- Used ReactIs to build a weather app using weather API for data
- · Implemented search functionality to find weather in cities all over the world
- Used CSS3 and Bootstrap 4 to improve user interface

SOLITAIRE GAME

- Used Pygame library in Python to build a fully functional solitaire card game
- · Implemented object oriented programming for cards, decks, and piles

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE

- Built a portfolio website(<u>rvanshim.ca</u>) using HTML5, CSS3, and, the Bootstrap 4 framework
- Website implements grid system, Javascript animations, visually appealing layouts, and external fonts and icons

MICROSOFT OFFICE

- Strong excel skills shown by making spread sheets for work schedules as a camp counsellor
- Demonstrated ability to make engaging PowerPoint presentations in courses at school

All programming projects can be found on my Github: github.com/RyanShim2000

EXPERIENCES

EVENT COORDINATOR | UNIONVILLE YOUTH COUNCIL | OCTOBER 2017 - MAY 2018

- Organized, led, and promoted face painting and balloon animal events for two hundred children
- Managed four hundred dollars towards props: painting kits and balloons for participating children
- · Delegated different roles to team members of the council based on their strengths and abilities

CAMP COUNSELLOR | JUST FOR KIDS CAMP | SUMMER 2015 - 2017

- Demonstrated leadership abilities by promoting safety to campers when facilitating activities
- Built a large-scale snack menu that could feed over one hundred fifty campers

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

ARCHITECTURAL ENGINEERING CLASS REPRESENTATIVE AT WATERLOO UNIVERSITY | SEPTEMBER 2018 – PRESENT

Managed \$100,000 school funds with other engineering programs for student aid

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ARCHITECTURAL ENGINEERING, BASC | UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO | ANTICIPATED 2023